Kael mss., 1939-2001 LMC 3004
Lilly Library
- II. Directors
  - Téchiné, André (Box 74)
    - Clippings concerning other films (Box 74)
  - Temple, Julien (Box 74)
    - Absolute Beginners., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 74)
    - Earth Girls Are Easy., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 74)
  - Teshigahara, Hiroshi (Box 74)
    - Suna no onna (Woman in the Dunes - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 74)
  - Thom, Robert (Box 74)
    - Angel, Angel, Down We Go., press release (Box 74)
    - Clipping concerning Thom (Box 74)
  - Thomas, Ralph L. (Box 74)
    - The Terry Fox Story., publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 74)
    - Ticket to Heaven., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 74)
  - Thompson, J. Lee (Box 74)
    - Eye of the Devil., notes, publicity (Box 74)
    - Woman in a Dressing Gown., photographs, clippings (Box 74)
    - Materials concerning other films, (see also: Box 116) (Box 74)
  - Thorpe, Richard (Box 74)
    - Night Must Fall., photographs (Box 74)
  - Till, Eric (Box 74)
    - Improper Channels., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 74)
  - Toback, James (Box 74)
    - The Big Bang., notes, press release, photographs, clippings (Box 74)
    - Black and White., clippings (Box 74)
  - Toback, James (cont.) (Box 75)
    - Exposed., (2 folders) (see also: Box 116) (Box 75)
    - Fingers., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
    - The Pick-up Artist., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 75)
    - Materials concerning other films and Toback (Box 75)
  - Tokar, Norman (Box 75)
    - The Ugly Dachshund., publicity (Box 75)
  - Torn, Rip (Box 75)
    - The Telephone., publicity (Box 75)
  - Tourneur, Maurice (Box 75)
    - Materials concerning various films (Box 75)
  - Towne, Robert (Box 75)
    - Ask the Dust., script (Box 75)
    - Personal Best., (3 folders) (Box 75)
    - Tequila Sunrise., (4 folders) (Box 75)
    - Materials concerning other films and Towne (Box 75)
  - Townsend, Robert (Box 75)
    - Eddie Murphy Raw., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 75)
    - Hollywood Shuffle., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
  - Toyoda, Shirô (Box 75)
    - Gan (The Mistress - U.S.)., photographs (Box 75)
  - Tramont, Jean-Claude (Box 75)
    - All Night Long., (4 folders) (Box 75)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Tramont (Box 75)
  - Trent, Barbara and David Kasper (Box 75)
    - Cover Up., press release, press kit (Box 75)
  - Troell, Jan (Box 75)
    - Bang!, press kit (Box 75)
    - Ingenjör Andrées luftfärd (The Flight of the Eagle - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
    - Nybyggarna (The New Land)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
    - Utvandrarna (The Emigrants - U.S.)., press release, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
    - Materials concerning other films (Box 75)
  - Truffaut, François (Box 75)
    - Baisers volés (Stolen Kisses - U.S.)., notes, press release, clippings (Box 75)
    - La Chambre verte (The Green Room - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 75)
    - Le Dernier métro (The Last Metro - U.S.)., (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Les Deux anglaises et le continent (Two English Girls - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
    - Domicile conjugal (Bed & Board - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 75)
    - L'Enfant sauvage (The Wild Child - U.S.)., press release, clippings (Box 75)
    - Fahrenheit 451., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 75)
    - La Femme d'à côté (The Woman Next Door - U.S.)., (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - L'Histoire d'Adèle H (The Story of Adele H - U.S.)., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 75)
    - L'Homme qui aimait les femmes (The Man Who Loved Women - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 75)
    - Jules et Jim (Jules and Jim - U.S.)., notes, program, printed item, clippings (Box 75)
  - Truffaut, François (cont.) (Box 76)
    - La Nuit américaine (Day for Night - U.S.)., notes, press release, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 76)
    - La Peau douce (The Soft Skin - U.S.)., printed item, clippings (Box 76)
    - Les Quatre cents coups (The 400 Blows - U.S.)., notes, publicity, printed item, photographs, clippings (Box 76)
    - Tirez sur le pianiste (Shoot the Piano Player - U.S.)., notes, printed item, clippings (Box 76)
    - Une belle fille comme moi (Such a Gorgeous Kid Llike Me - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Vivement dimanche! (Confidentially Yours - U.S.)., notes, press release, clippings (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning other films and Truffaut, (2 folders) (see also: Box 116) (Box 76)
  - Trumbo, Dalton (Box 76)
    - Clippings concerning various films and Trumbo (Box 76)
  - Trumbull, Douglas (Box 76)
    - Brainstorm., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
  - Tsukerman, Slava (Box 76)
    - Liquid Sky., publicity, clippings (Box 76)
  - Tuggle, Richard (Box 76)
    - Tightrope., notes, press release, program, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
  - Uher, Stefan (Box 76)
    - Keby som mal pusku (If I Had A Gun - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
  - Vadim, Roger (Box 76)
    - Clippings concerning various films, (see also: Box 116) (Box 76)
  - Van Citters, Darrell (Box 76)
    - Box-Office Bunny (see: The NeverEnding Story II: The Next Chapter) (Box 76)
  - Van Dyke, W.S. (Box 76)
    - It's a Wonderful World., photographs (Box 76)
    - The Thin Man., photographs, printed item, clippings (Box 76)
  - Van Horn, Buddy (Box 76)
    - Any Which Way You Can., press release, press kit, photographs, clippings (Box 76)
    - The Dead Pool., press release, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
    - Pink Cadillac., press release, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
  - Van Peebles, Melvin (Box 76)
    - Sweet Sweetback's Baadasssss Song., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - Clippings concerning other films (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning Van Peebles (Box 76)
  - Van Sant, Gus (Box 76)
    - Drugstore Cowboy., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Mala Noche., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - My Own Private Idaho., publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 76)
  - Varda, Agnès (Box 76)
    - La Bonheur (Happiness - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - Cléo de 5 à 7 (Cleo from 5 to 7 - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - Les Crétures (The Creatures - U.S.)., photographs, clippings (Box 76)
    - Kung-Fu master., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Murs, murs (Mural Murals) and Daguerréotypes., press release, clippings (Box 76)
    - Sans toit ni loi (Vagabond - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Ulysse., press release, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - L'une chante, l'autre pas (One Sings, the Other Doesn't - U.S.)., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning other films and Varda (Box 76)
  - Verhoeven, Michael (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning various films (Box 76)
  - Verhoeven, Paul (Box 76)
    - Flesh & Blood., clippings (Box 76)
    - Keetje Tippel., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - RoboCop., (2 folders) (Box 76)
    - Soldaat van Oranje (Soldier of Orange - U.S.)., publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 76)
    - Spetters., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - Total Recall., press kit, clippings (Box 76)
    - De Vierde man (The 4th Man - U.S.)., publicity, clippings (Box 76)
  - Vidor, King (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning various films and Vidor (Box 76)
  - Vigne, Daniel (Box 76)
    - Le Retour de Martin Guerre (The Return of Martin Guerre - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Une femme ou deux (One Woman or Two - U.S.)., clippings (Box 76)
  - Vigo, Jean (Box 76)
    - L'Atalante., printed item, program, clippings (Box 76)
    - Zéro de conduite: Jeunes diables au college (Zero for Conduct - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 76)
    - Printed items and Clippings concerning both L'Atalante and Zéro de conduite:... (Box 76)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Vigo (Box 76)
  - Visconti, Luchino (Box 76)
    - La Caduta degli dei (The Damned - U.S.)., publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Il Gattopardo (The Leopard - U.S.)., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
    - Gruppo di famiglia in un interno (Conversation Piece - U.S.)., program, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - L'Innocente (The Innocent - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Ludwig., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
    - Morte a Venezia (Death in Venice - U.S.)., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Rocco e i suoi fratelli (Rocco and His Brothers - U.S.)., notes, printed item, clippings (Box 76)
    - La Terra trema: Episodio del mare (The Earth Will Tremble - U.S.)., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning other films (Box 76)
    - Clippings concerning Visconti (Box 76)
  - Von Trotta, Margarethe (Box 76)
    - Materials concerning various films (Box 76)
  - WNET (New York City) (Box 76)
    - The Silent Years - TV series., notes, printed item, clipping (Box 76)
  - Wadleigh, Michael (Box 76)
    - Wolfen., notes, press release, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 76)
    - Woodstock: The Lost Performances., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
  - Wagner, Jane (Box 76)
    - Moment by Moment., notes, reader's report, publicity, clippings (Box 76)
  - Wajda, Andrzej (Box 77)
    - Czlowiek z marmuru (Man of Marble - U.S.)., publicity, clippings (Box 77)
    - Czlowiek z zelaza (Man of Iron - U.S.)., clippings (Box 77)
    - Danton., clippings (Box 77)
    - Popiól i diament (Ashes and Diamonds - U.S.)., printed item, clippings (Box 77)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Wajda, (2 folders) (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
  - Waletzky, Joshua (Box 77)
    - Image Before My Eyes., notes, press release, printed items, clippings (Box 77)
  - Walker, Nancy (Box 77)
    - Can't Stop the Music., (2 folders) (Box 77)
  - Wallace, Tommy Lee (Box 77)
    - Halloween III: Season of the Witch., publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 77)
  - Wallace, Richard (Box 77)
    - Wedding Present., notes (Box 77)
  - Walsh, Raoul (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning various films (Box 77)
  - Warhol, Andy (Box 77)
    - Clippings concerning various films and Warhol, (2 folders) (see also: (Box 77)
  - Waters, John (Box 77)
    - Cry-Baby., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 77)
    - Hairspray., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning other films (Box 77)
    - Clippings concerning Waters (Box 77)
  - Watkins, Peter (Box 77)
    - Edvard Munch., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 77)
    - Privilege., (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
    - Punishment Park., notes, clippings (Box 77)
    - The War Game., (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning Watkins (Box 77)
  - Weber, Bruce (Box 77)
    - Broken Noses., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 77)
    - Let's Get Lost., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 77)
  - Weir, Peter (Box 77)
    - Dead Poets Society., (2 folders) (Box 77)
    - Gallipoli., notes, clippings (Box 77)
    - Green Card., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 77)
    - The Last Wave., press kit, clippings (Box 77)
    - The Mosquito Coast., (2 folders) (Box 77)
    - Witness., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 77)
    - The Year of Living Dangerously., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning other films and Weir (Box 77)
  - Welles, Orson (Box 77)
    - Citizen Kane, (see: Box 81 and 82) (Box 77)
    - Campanadas a medianoche (Chimes at Midnight - U.K.), list of credits, synopsis, clippings (Box 77)
    - The Lady from Shanghai., photographs, clippings (Box 77)
    - Macbeth., (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
    - Magnificent Ambersons., (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
    - Touch of Evil., program, photographs, clippings (Box 77)
    - The Tragedy of Othello: The Moor of Venice., (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
    - The Trial., clippings (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning other films (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning Welles, (see: Box 81 and 82 ) (Box 77)
  - Wellman, William A. (Box 77)
    - Nothing Sacred., photographs (Box 77)
    - The Ox-Bow Incident., (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
    - Public Enemy., printed item, photographs (Box 77)
    - Roxie Hart., photographs, clippings (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning other films and Wellman, (see also: Box 116) (Box 77)
  - Wenders, Wim (Box 77)
    - Der Amerikanische Freund (The American Friend - U.S.)., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 77)
    - Hammett., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 77)
    - Der Himmel über Berlin (Wings of Desire - U.S.)., notes, press release, clippings (Box 77)
    - The Million Dollar Hotel., script (Box 77)
    - Paris, Texas., notes, press release, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 77)
    - Der Stand der Dinge (The State of Things - U.S.)., press release, publicity, clippings (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning other films (Box 77)
    - Materials concerning Wenders (Box 77)
  - Wendkos, Paul (Box 77)
    - Notes for various films (Box 77)
  - Wexler, Haskell (Box 77)
    - Medium Cool., notes, printed item, clippings (Box 77)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Wexler (Box 77)
  - Whale, James (Box 78)
    - Frankenstein., printed item, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Old Dark House., photographs (Box 78)
    - The Road Back., (see: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - Show Boat., photographs, clippings (Box 78)
  - Widerberg, Bo (Box 78)
    - Joe Hill., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Materials concerning other films and Widerberg (Box 78)
  - Wiederhorn, Ken (Box 78)
    - Eyes of a Stranger., press kit (Box 78)
  - Wiene, Robert (Box 78)
    - Das Cabinet des Dr. Caligari (The Cabinet of Dr. Caligari - U.S.)., photographs, printed item, clippings (Box 78)
  - Wilder, Billy (Box 78)
    - Ace in the Hole., photographs, clippings (Box 78)
    - Fedora., notes, clippings (Box 78)
    - A Foreign Affair., photographs (Box 78)
    - The Fortune Cookie., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Front Page., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Kiss Me, Stupid., notes, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Lost Weekend., (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - One, Two, Three., (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - Some Like It Hot., (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - Sunset Boulevard., (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Wilder, (2 folders) (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
  - Wilder, Gene (Box 78)
    - The Adventure of Sherlock Holmes' Smarter Brother., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Haunted Honeymoon., press release, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Woman in Red., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - The World's Greatest Lover., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Materials concerning Wilder (Box 78)
  - Williams, Emlyn (Box 78)
    - The Last Days of Dolwyn (Women of Dolwyn - U.S.)., publicity, photographs (Box 78)
    - Clippings concerning Williams (Box 78)
  - Williams, Oscar (Box 78)
    - Hot Potato., publicity, photographs (Box 78)
  - Williams, Paul (Box 78)
    - Dealing: Or the Berkeley-to-Boston Forty-Brick Lost-Bag Blues., notes (Box 78)
  - Willis, Gordon (Box 78)
    - Windows., notes, clippings (Box 78)
  - Wilson, Hugh (Box 78)
    - Burglar., press release, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - Police Academy., press release, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - Rustlers' Rhapsody., notes, press release, clippings (Box 78)
  - Wincer, Simon (Box 78)
    - Phar Lap., Statement from American Humane Association; photographs, clippings (Box 78)
  - Wise, Robert (Box 78)
    - The Body Snatcher., photographs (Box 78)
    - The Sound of Music., notes (Box 78)
    - Three Secrets., notes (Box 78)
  - Wolk, Andy (Box 78)
    - Criminal Justice (television)., notes (Box 78)
  - Wood, Sam (Box 78)
    - A Day at the Races., program, photographs, clippings (Box 78)
    - Goodbye Mr. Chips., photographs (Box 78)
    - A Night at the Opera., printed item, photographs (Box 78)
    - Saratoga Trunk., photographs, clippings (Box 78)
  - Wrye, Donald (Box 78)
    - The Entertainer., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
  - Wyler, William (Box 78)
    - Carrie., (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - Funny Girl., publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Heiress., photographs, clippings (Box 78)
    - Jezebel., photographs, clippings (Box 78)
    - Wuthering Heights., (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - Materials concerning other films and Wyler, (2 folders) (see also: Box 116) (Box 78)
  - Yates, Pamela and Newton Thomas Sigel (Box 78)
    - John and Mary., (see: Box 116) (Box 78)
    - When the Mountains Tremble., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
  - Yates, Peter (Box 78)
    - Breaking Away., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Bullitt., notes, program, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Deep., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Dresser., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Eleni., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 78)
    - Eyewitness., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 78)
    - For Pete's Sake., notes, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Friends of Eddie Coyle., publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - The Hot Rock., publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - The House on Carroll Street., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - An Innocent Man., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - John and Mary., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Suspect., press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - Materials concerning other films and Yates (Box 78)
  - Yosha, Yaki (Box 78)
    - Ha-Ayit (The Vulture)., clippings (Box 78)
    - Sus Etz (Rockinghorse)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
  - Young Harold (Box 78)
    - The Scarlet Pimpernel., photographs (Box 78)
  - Young, Robert M. (Box 78)
    - The Ballad of Gregorio Cortez., publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - Extremities., notes, clippings (Box 78)
    - One Trick Pony., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 78)
    - Rich Kids., notes, clippings (Box 78)
    - Short Eyes., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 78)
    - Materials concerning other films (Box 78)
  - Zampi, Mario (Box 79)
    - Laughter in Paradise., publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 79)
    - The Naked Truth (Your Past is Showing - U.S.)., notes, photographs, clippings (Box 79)
  - Zanussi, Krzysztoff (Box 79)
    - Barwy ochronne (Camouflage - U.S.)., notes, press release, clippings (Box 79)
    - Kontrakt (The Contract - U.S.)., notes, press release, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - Wege in der Nacht (Ways in the Night - U.S.)., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Zanussi (Box 79)
  - Zarpas, Ted (Box 79)
    - Elektra., notes, photographs (Box 79)
  - Zeffirelli, Franco (Box 79)
    - The Champ., (for publicity see: Box 116) (Box 79)
    - Endless Love., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - Otello., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - The Taming of the Shrew., (see also: Box 116) (Box 79)
    - La Traviata., press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Materials concerning other films and Zeffirelli, (see also: Box 116) (Box 79)
  - Zeman, Karel (Box 79)
    - Bláznova kronika (A Jester's Tale - International English)., photographs (Box 79)
    - Vynález zkázy (A Deadly Invention - International English; The Fabulous World of Jules Verne - U.S.)., notes, clippings (Box 79)
  - Zemeckis, Robert (Box 79)
    - Back to the Future., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Back to the Future II., notes, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Back to the Future III., press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Romancing the Stone., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Used Cars., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 79)
    - Clippings concerning other films and Zemeckis (Box 79)
  - Zetterling Mai (Box 79)
    - Nattlek (Night Games - U.S.)., publicity, clippings (Box 79)
  - Zieff, Howard (Box 79)
    - The Dream Team., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Hearts of the West., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - House Calls., press release, clippings (Box 79)
    - The Main Event., publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 79)
    - Private Benjamin., notes, publicity, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Slither., press release, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - Unfaithfully Yours., notes, publicity, photographs, clippings (Box 79)
  - Zinnemann, Fred (Box 79)
    - The Day of the Jackal., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - Five Days One Summer., (2 folders) (Box 79)
    - From Here to Eternity., (see also: Box 116) (Box 79)
    - High Noon., photographs, clippings (Box 79)
    - Julia., notes, publicity, clippings (Box 79)
    - The Member of the Wedding., (see also: Box 116) (Box 79)
    - Materials concerning other films and Zinnemann, (2 folders) (see also: Box 116) (Box 79)
  - Zucker, David (Box 79)
    - The Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad!, clippings (Box 79)
  - Zulawski, Andrzej (Box 79)
    - Possession., press kit (Box 79)
  - Zuniga, Frank (Box 79)
    - The Golden Seal., press release (Box 79)
  - Zurlini, Valerio (Box 79)
    - Clippings concerning various films (Box 79)
  - Zwick, Edward (Box 79)
    - About Last Night..., notes, press release, press kit, clippings (Box 79)
    - Glory., (for publicity see: Box 116) (Box 79)
  - unidentified director (Box 79)
    - Donald Duck's 50th Birthday (television)., press kit (Box 79)
  - unidentified director and film., (see: Box 116) (Box 79)
- Directors, A - E (Box 113 Oversize)
- Directors, F - K (Box 114 Oversize)
- Directors, L - Re (Box 115 Oversize)
- Directors, Ri - Z (Box 116 Oversize)
- Directors, A - Z (Box 121 Oversize)
- Oversize folio: Directors, A - Z (Box 124 Oversize)
- III. Writings
  Arranged as follows: "An Index...," early writings, articles for magazines, book reviews, interviews (with Kael), lectures/speeches, panel discussions, film series, notes, and miscellaneous. Most of the Kael's notes may be found under the specific film title filed throughout Series II. Directors.
  - "An Index to the Film Reviews of Pauline Kael" by Claire Dorton, 1989; (2 folders) (Box 80)
  - Early writings., (4 folders) (Box 80)
  - Articles., Contains complete magazines and/or tear sheets.
    Arranged alphabetically by title of magazine or journal.
    - The American Review, Oct. 1965; Are Movies Going to Pieces (Box 80)
    - Atlantic, Dec. 1964; Are Movies Going to Pieces (Box 80)
    - The Austin Chronicle, Nov. 19, 1999; (see: Box 122) (Box 80)
    - DialogueVol. 4, No. 1., 1971; Trash, Art and the Movies (Box 80)
    - Holiday, Mar. 1966; (see: Box 117) (Box 80)
    - Mademoiselle, July 1965; Old Movies Never Die (Box 80)
    - Modern Writing, 1954; Movies, The Desperate Art (Box 80)
    - The New Republic, 1966-1967; Tear sheets (Box 80)
    - The New Yorker magazine., Mostly tear sheets: (Box 80)
      - Conversations: The Wild Man, Remembering Peckinpah., Nov. 8, 1999 (Box 80)
      - Current Cinema. Mostly tear sheets and some corrected page proofs., 1969-1990; (9 folders) (For "Current Cinema" written by other authors, see: IV. Writings by Others. Current Cinema) (Box 80)
      - Onward and Upward With the Arts: Bonnie and Clyde, Oct. 21, 1967; tear sheets (Box 80)
      - Onward and Upward With the Arts: Movies on Television, June 3, 1967; tear sheets (Box 80)
      - Onward and Upward With the Arts: On the Future of Movies, Aug. 5, 1974; tear sheets (Box 80)
      - Onward and Upward With the Arts: Raising Kane, (see: The Citizen Kane Book) (Box 80)
      - Profiles: The Man from Dream CityReprinted in Washington Star, July 14, 1975; July 11, 1976; tear sheets (Box 80)
    - The Observer, Nov. 30, 1980; Why the Movies Are So Bad... Also contains page proof (Box 80)
    - Performing Arts Journal, May/Sept. 1995; It's Only a Movie (Box 80)
    - Saturday Night at the Movies, 1980-81; Movies on Television (Box 80)